<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Journey on (ง •̀_•́)ง Ming and Her Code</title>
    <link>https://mingyong.dev/journey/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Journey on (ง •̀_•́)ง Ming and Her Code</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2021, Ming Yong.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mingyong.dev/journey/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>As an Intern: Why should we keep you?</title>
      <link>https://mingyong.dev/journey/chapter3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mingyong.dev/journey/chapter3/</guid>
      <description>I believe you are not &amp;ldquo;less valuable&amp;rdquo; just because you don&amp;rsquo;t have much experience in the field (yet). Everybody provides different values to the team.
The one thing you can always do is save people&amp;rsquo;s time. During my internship, I follow these two principles:
 Do not waste people&amp;rsquo;s time. Save people&amp;rsquo;s time if I can. Deliver work that&amp;rsquo;s valuable even after I left the company.  Here are a list of things I did besides coding:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>As a Student: Good GPA, but what else?</title>
      <link>https://mingyong.dev/journey/chapter2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mingyong.dev/journey/chapter2/</guid>
      <description>I went to St.Lawrence College for the Computer Programmer Analyst advanced diploma program in 2018. As an international student, surviving winter in Canada and surviving school became my goals in my first year.
School is going well after I figured out how the system works. Now I can focus on preparing for the work placement program in our last two semesters.
It didn&amp;rsquo;t take me long to realized that GPA is not the key selling point in community college.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>As a Code Newbie: What makes a good developer?</title>
      <link>https://mingyong.dev/journey/chapter1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mingyong.dev/journey/chapter1/</guid>
      <description>Content  The plan The process Appendix A: Projects I built Appendix B: Notes I took Appendix C: For memories  The plan As a code newbie, the questions I have are :
 What hard skills do I need besides what&amp;rsquo;s taught in school? What soft skills do a developer need? How can I build them?  The answer to question 1 is pretty simple: take a look at the program outline and learn what&amp;rsquo;s not on there.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
